<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | Sönke Rohde]]></title>
  <link href="http://srohde.github.io/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://srohde.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-25T22:00:40-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://srohde.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sönke Rohde]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[zsh shell]]></title>
    <link href="http://srohde.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/zsh-shell/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T09:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://srohde.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/zsh-shell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The terminal is next to the editor probably the most important tool for a developer. Being comfortable executing shell commands increases productivty significantly. And that&rsquo;s what it&rsquo;s about at the end. Being able to focus on solving the problem and not dealing with tools and workflows to get there. For a long time I am using <a href="http://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm 2</a> but that&rsquo;s only the terminal and does not change the actuall shell.</p>

<p>I was browsing <a href="http://dotfiles.github.io/">dotfiles</a> and came across <a href="http://zsh.sourceforge.net/">zsh</a>, an alternative to the default bash shell on OSX.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been using zsh for a couple of weeks now and like especially the dot-files <a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">oh-my-zsh</a> which provide a great default configuration and git prompts. Here the steps on how I&rsquo;ve set things up:</p>

<p>Make zsh default shell:</p>

<pre><code>chsh -s /bin/zsh
</code></pre>

<p>Open a new terminal window to see zsh!</p>

<p>Install oh-my-zsh (you gotta trust that script so make sure you want to do that):</p>

<pre><code>curl -L https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/raw/master/tools/install.sh | sh
</code></pre>

<p>Now some configiration. Edit <code>~/zshrc</code>.
I like the default theme but set <code>ZSH_THEME="random"</code> and open some new shells to explore some other themes you might like better.</p>

<p>Oh-my-zsh comes with a bunch of plugins and only a few are set by default.
Here is my plugin list:</p>

<pre><code>plugins=(cake git sublime osx git-flow git-extras npm node theme web-search battery)
</code></pre>

<p>I always use the <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2</a> plugin which just creates a <code>st</code> alias.</p>

<p>The web-search plugin is quite nice since now you can <code>google</code> or <code>bing</code> from the command line:</p>

<pre><code>$ google bing
$ bing google
</code></pre>

<p>Explore all the plugins in <code>~/.oh-my-zsh/plugins</code> to enable what fits your workflow. I discovered <a href="https://github.com/visionmedia/git-extras">git-extras</a> doing this which is really awesome.</p>

<p>If you want to use <a href="https://github.com/rupa/z">z</a> here two lines how to set it up:</p>

<pre><code>git clone git@github.com:rupa/z.git ~/.z
echo \\n. ~/.z/z.sh &gt;&gt; ~/.zshrc
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
